Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Albert Cornell, M.D., 1938-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Collection of Albert Cornell, M.D. 1938-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cornell, Albert
4 linear feet Extent: 1500 Items
Retired Chief of the Gastrointestinal Clinic at Mount Sinai Hospital. Collection consists of medical and pharmaceutical advertisements and promotional materials. Included are posters, booklets, and promotional emphemera. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Advertising, Sales & Marketing History.
cornella
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Collection of Albert Cornell, M.D. were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
Dr. Cornell was a consultant in gastroenterology at the Mount Sinai Medical Center and the retired Chief of the Gastrointestinal Clinic at Mount Sinai Hospital.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of medical and pharmaceutical advertisements and promotional materials. Included are posters, booklets, and promotional emphemera. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Advertising, Sales & Marketing History.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Cornell, Albert; Advertising -- Medicine; Advertising -- Health products; Advertising -- Pharmaceutical industry; Calendars; Posters; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2006-0094), 9 Boxes
  Collection consists of medical and pharmaceutical advertisements. primarily posters, booklets and ephemera. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Advertising, Sales & Marketing History.
  - Collateral literature and advertising materials from pharmaceutical and other medical companies, 1950s-1960s (Box 1)
  - Printed materials and journals, 1952-1966
  - Notepads, 1970-1987 (Box 2)
  - Appointment book, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Pharmaceutical and other medical advertising materials
  - Physician's handbook
  - Advertising ephemera (Box 4)
    Rulers, pens, nail clippers, and other household items.
  - Advertising ephemera (Box 5)
    Golf balls, pens, drug trays, a large nut and bolt, and other promotional materials.
  - Silverware from Mount Sinai Hospital
  - Advertising ephemera (Box 6)
    Trays, mugs, cups, and other materials.
  - Calendars, 1961-1982 (Box 7)
  - Posters (Box 8)
  - Posters (Box 9)